



people | projects | facility | publications | outreach | sponsors | contact

PROF. DANIELE FACCIO



Professor in Quantum Technologies

address:
Kelvin Building
School of Physics and
Astronomy
College of Science and
Engineering
University of Glasgow
Glasgow, G12 8QQ
United Kingdom
Tel: daniele.faccio@glasgow.ac.uk

Research ID: Google Scholar

BIOGRAPHY

Daniele Faccio joined the University of Glasgow in 2018. He is a Professor in Quantum Technologies, adjunct professor at the University of Arizona, Tucson (USA) and was elected Fellow of the Royal Society of Edinburgh in 2017. He was previously professor in Physics at Heriot-Watt University (Edinburgh, UK, 2010-2017) and assistant professor at the University of Insubria (Como, Italy, 2004-2010). He has also been visiting scientist at MIT (USA), Marie-Curie fellow at ICFO, Barcelona (Spain) and ERC fellow 2012-2017. He was awarded the Philip Leverhulme Prize in Physics in 2015 and the Royal Society of Edinburgh Senior Public Engagement medal in 2017.

EDUCATION

Graduate Ph.D, University of Nice-Sophia Antipolis, France (2004 -2007); Prof. J. Tredicce (Advisor)

Undergraduate M.Phil. (Physics) Optoelectronics Research Centre, Southampton University, UK (1999 -2001)

Undergraduate M.Sc. (Hons. Physics) Universita' degli Studi di Milano, Italy, (1992 -1998)

PREVIOUS APPOINTMENTS

Professor in Physics Heriot-Watt University, Edinbrugh (2013-2017) **Reader in Physics** Heriot-Watt University, Edinbrugh (2010-2013) **Assistant Professor** University of Insubria, Italy (2004-2010) **Visiting Professor** FORTH Laser Institute, Crete, Greece (2010) Visiting Scientist Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Boston, USA (2002)

Research Scientist Pirelli Labs - Optical technologies, Milan, Italy (2003-2004)

Research Scientist Corning, Milan, Italy (2001-2002)

AWARDS AND PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

Elected Fellow of the Royal Society of Edinburgh, 2017 Royal Society of Edinburgh Senior public Engagement award, 2017 Philip Leverhulme Prize, 2015

Co-director of the Enrico Fermi Summer School, Frontiers of Modern Optics, Varenna, Italy (2010)

Co-director of Summer School on Analogue Gravity, Como, Italy (2010) Marie Curie Fellowship, awarded by European Community (2009)

Co-director of STELLA, Experimental School in Laser Physics, FORTH Laser Centre, Greece (2008)

Editor, Scientific Reports (2012-2017)

Summer School Lecturer, Optoelectronics - Crete (2006), STELLA experimental school in Laser

Physics - Vilnius (2007), FORTH Laser facility, Crete (2008), ICFO Barcelona (2009)



SUPA) member of SUPA research alliance in Physics | Contact | ©2010 Daniele Faccio